University of Connecticut, School of Social Work Records 1998.0105
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
University of Connecticut, School of Social Work Records
undated, 1947-2001
1998.0105
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
3.1 Linear feet
Established in 1946, the School of Social Work is located on the Greater Hartford campus of the University of Connecticut. The University of Connecticut School of Social Work promotes social and economic justice by providing high quality education in social work. The School prepares competent professionals with knowledge, as well as general and specialized method skills for helping people enrich their lives, improve their communities, and contribute to a more just social order.
University of Connecticut, School of Social Work.
History
Established in 1946, the University of Connecticut School of Social Work presently offers a two-year program leading to the degree of Master of Social Work and special programs for non-matriculated students. Workshops, institutes, and continuing education courses are regularly offered for social service personnel at various levels of education preparation. The School is accredited by the Council on Social Work Education.
Specifics about the School may be found on their website.
Scope and Content
The collection contains minutes, reports, administrative, financial and accreditation records for the School dating, primarily, from the late 1960s through the late 1970s. Publications from the School have been cataloged and may be located by searching the Libraries online catalog, Homer.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as received.
Series I: Records ( undated, 1947-1998 )
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Annual Report Dodd Periodicals
Bulletin Dodd Periodicals
Acquisition Information
The records have been transferred to the University Archives from the School periodically.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
University of Connecticut. School of Social Work.; Administrative records.; Connecticut.; Education.; Financial Records.; Publications.; Social sciences--Study and teaching (Graduate)--Connecticut.; Social work education--Connecticut.; Social workers--Education (Graduate)--Connecticut.; Universities and colleges.; West Hartford (Conn.)--Education--Universities and colleges.
- Series I: Records, undated, 1947-2001
  - 50th Anniversary materials, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Accreditation Report, 1965, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Educational Policy Committee, 1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Development Committee minutes, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Curriculum Committee minutes, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dean's Advisory Committee minutes, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Human Behavior and Social Environment Committee minutes, 1969-1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Committee List, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Casework Sequence Meetings minutes, 1968-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1947-1988 (Box 2, Folder 15-22)
  - Minutes, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - On-site visit report, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Publications, 1964-1992 (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
  - Proposal for Ph.D. in Social Work, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Research Committee, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Social Work Leadership for Human Service Management in the 1990s: The Challenge of the new demographic reality, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Student Handbook, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Student Organization minutes, 1995 July - 2001 June
    - 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 30)